[
    {
        "question": "1. What is cryptography?",
        "answer": "Cryptography refers to the domain of cyber security that serves the purpose of safeguarding information from individuals known as adversaries, thereby ensuring that the data is exclusively accessed by only senders and intended recipients.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "2. What is a traceroute? Mention its uses.",
        "answer": "Traceroute is a network diagnostic tool that helps track the route taken by a packet sent across the IP network. It also shows the IP addresses of all the routers it pinged between the source and the destination.\nUses: \nIt shows the time taken by the packet for each hop during the transmission. \nWhen the packet is lost during the transmission, the traceroute will identify the point of failure.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "3. What is a firewall? Mention its uses.",
        "answer": "In cybersecurity, a firewall refers to a type of network security system that blocks malicious traffic from hackers and hence maintains the data privacy. This includes bots, phishing links, worms viruses, malware, trojan viruses, etc.\nUses: \nThe firewall monitors the inbound and outbound network traffic. It permits or allows only data packets agreeable to the set of security guidelines the server owner sets.\nA firewall acts as a barrier between the internal network and the inbound traffic from external sources like the Internet.\nEnroll in our Cyber Security course to learn from experts and get certified!",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "4. What is a three-way handshake?",
        "answer": "It is a process that happens in a TCP/IP network when you make a connection between a local host and the server. It is a three-step process to negotiate the acknowledgment and synchronization of packets before communication starts. \n\nStep 1: The client makes a connection with the server with SYN.\nStep 2: The server responds to the client’s request with SYN+ACK.\nStep 3: The client acknowledges the server’s response with ACK, and the actual data transmission begins.\nGet 100% Hike!\nMaster Most in Demand Skills Now !\nBy providing your contact details, you agree to our Terms of Use & Privacy Policy",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "5. What is a response code? List them.",
        "answer": "HTTP response codes indicate a server’s response when a client makes a request to the server. It shows whether an HTTP request is completed or not. \n1xx: Informational\nThe request is received, and the process continues. Some example codes are:\n100 (continue)\n101 (switching protocol)\n102 (processing)\n103 (early hints)\n2xx: Success \nThe action is received, understood, and accepted successfully. A few example codes for this are:\n200 (OK)\n202 (accepted)\n205 (reset content)\n208 (already reported)\n3xx: Redirection \nTo complete the request, further action is required to take place. Example codes:\n300 (multiple choice)\n302 (found)\n308 (permanent redirect)\n4xx: Client Error \nThe request has incorrect syntax, or it is not fulfilled. Here are the example codes for this:\n400 (bad request)\n403 (forbidden)\n404 (not found)\n5xx: Server Error \nThe server fails to complete a valid request. Example codes for this are:\n500 (internal server error)\n502 (bad gateway)\n511 (network authentication required)\nElevate your interview preparedness with us. Check out our YouTube video on Cyber Security Interview Questions:",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "6. What is the CIA triad?",
        "answer": "CIA Triad is a security model to ensure IT security. CIA stands for confidentiality, integrity, and availability.\nConfidentiality: To protect sensitive information from unauthorized access.\nIntegrity: To protect data from deletion or modification by an unintended person.\nAvailability: To confirm the availability of the data whenever needed.\nAlso, check out this blog for Top Cyber Security Skills!",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "7. Name various types of cyberattacks.",
        "answer": "Here is a list of common cyberattacks aimed at inflicting damage to a system. \nMan in the Middle attack: The attacker puts himself in the communication between the sender and the receiver. This is done to eavesdrop and impersonate to steal data. \nPhishing: Here, the attacker will act as a trusted entity to perform malicious activities such as getting usernames, passwords, and credit card numbers.\nRogue Software: It is a fraudulent attack where the attacker fakes a virus on the target device and offers an anti-virus tool to remove the malware. This is done to install malicious software into the system. \nMalware: Malware is software that is designed to attack the target system. The software can be a virus, worm, ransomware, spyware, and so on.\nDrive-by Downloads: The hacker takes advantage of the lack of updates on the OS, app, or browser, which automatically downloads malicious code to the system.\nDDoS: This is done to overwhelm the target network with massive traffic, making it impossible for the website or the service to be operable.\nMalvertising: Malvertising refers to the injections of maleficent code to legitimate advertising networks, which redirect users to unintended websites.\nPassword Attacks:  As the name suggests, here, the hacker obtain credentials like passwords.\nCheck out our blog on Cyber Security Tips and Best Practices to prevent Cyber Security attacks!",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "8. What is data leakage?",
        "answer": "Data leakage is the term used to describe the unauthorized release of data from a business to a third party. The internet, email, mobile data, as well as storage devices like USB keys, laptops, and optical discs, are just a few of the routes via which this transmission may take place.\nTypes of data leakage:\nAccidental leakage: The authorized entity sends data to an unauthorized entity accidentally.\nMalicious insiders: The authorized entity intentionally sends data to an unauthorized entity.\nElectronic communication: Hackers make use of hacking tools to intrude the system.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "9. Explain port scanning.",
        "answer": "A port scan helps you determine the ports that are open, listening, or closed on a network. Administrators use this to test network security and the system’s firewall strength. For hackers, it is a popular reconnaissance tool to identify the weak point to break into a system.\nSome of the common basic port scanning techniques are:\nUDP\nPing scan\nTCP connect\nTCP half-open\nStealth scanning\nCheck out this interesting blog on Ethical Hacking Tools now!",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "10. Explain brute force attacks and the ways to prevent them.",
        "answer": "A brute force attack is a hack where the attacker tries to guess the target password by trial and error. It is mostly implemented with the help of automated software used to login with credentials.\nHere are some ways to prevent a brute force attack:\nSet a lengthy password\nSet a high-complexity password\nSet a limit for login failures\n\nIntermediate Cyber Security Interview Questions",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "11. What is cryptography?",
        "answer": "",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "Cryptography is a domain of cyber security, and its main purpose is to keep information safe from individuals known as adversaries and ensure data is accessed by only senders and intended recipients.",
        "answer": "Are you looking to become a Cyber Security Expert? Go through Intellipaat’s MBA in Cyber Security Program!",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "12. What is a firewall? Mention its uses.",
        "answer": "A firewall in cybersecurity is like a wall that keeps track of incoming and outgoing traffic to block any malicious activity from hackers. This acts like a network security system that can maintain data privacy. Some malicious activities include bots, phishing links, worms viruses, malware, trojan viruses, etc.\nUses: \nFirewall checks if there are any data violations by monitoring the inbound and outbound network traffic. Data packets with an agreeable set of security guidelines set by the server owner are permitted.\nIt is like a wall, keeping the internal network and outer traffic separate from external sources like the internet.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "13. What is the CIA triad?",
        "answer": "The CIA in CIA Triad stands for confidentiality, integrity, and availability, which is one of the most common models used to ensure IT security. Let’s see what confidentiality, integrity, and availability mean:\nConfidentiality: This is mainly to protect private information from unauthorized access.\nIntegrity: This is all about the protection of data from being deleted or modified by unauthorized people. \nAvailability: This is to check if data is available when it’s required.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "14. Name various types of cyberattacks.",
        "answer": "Below is a list of cybersecurity attacks that aim to cause damage to the system.\nMan in the Middle Attack: As the name suggests, an attacker puts himself in the middle of the communication between the sender and receiver to steal data by eavesdropping.\nPhishing: This type of attack is when the attacker acts like someone trustworthy by sending links from reputed sources and then stealing your information, like usernames, passwords, and credit card numbers.\nRogue Software: This type of attack is when the attacker fakes by making the target believe they have a virus in their system and offers an anti-virus tool to remove the virus. This is done to install the malware software on the target’s system.\nMalware: This is software that is intentionally created to cause harm to the target’s system. The type of software can be a virus, worm, ransomware, spyware, and so on.\nDrive-by Downloads: This is a type of attack that occurs when the target unknowingly installs a virus. The hacker takes advantage of the lack of updates on OS, apps, or browsers, which can automatically install virus code into the system.\nDDoS: A Distributed Denial of Service attack is when the target’s network, for example, gets a huge amount of traffic at a time, forcing the website to reach its limit and not operate.\nMalvertising: This is a type of attack where a harmful malware code is injected into a legitimate advertisement, which will redirect a user to an unintended website.\nPassword Attacks: As the name suggests, the hacker takes advantage of the tendency of users to give easy passwords by researching their online-given information. This can then be used to access password-protected information.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "15. What is a response code? List them.",
        "answer": "An HTTP response code is a response that the server gives to a client’s request. It is indicated if an HTTP request is completed or not. Below are the code statuses and their categories:\n1xx: Informational\nThis tells us that the request has been received and the process can continue. Below are some of the sample code statuses:\n100 (continue)\n101 (switching protocol)\n102 (processing)\n103 (early hints)\n2xx: Success \nThis code indicates that the action was successful by receiving, understanding, and accepting the information.\n200 (OK)\n202 (accepted)\n205 (reset content)\n208 (already reported)\n3xx: Redirection \nThis code status indicates that to complete the request, an additional action is required. Below are some examples of the codes:\n300 (multiple choice)\n302 (found)\n308 (permanent redirect)\n4xx: Client Error \nThis indicates that the requested page couldn’t be reached or the request has a syntax error. Below are some of the code examples:\n400 (bad request)\n403 (forbidden)\n404 (not found)\n5xx: Server Error \nThis status is when the server is not able to complete the valid request. Below are some code examples:\n500 (internal server error)\n502 (bad gateway)\n511 (network authentication required)",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "16. What is a traceroute? Mention its uses.",
        "answer": "Traceroute is a network analytical tool that helps track the way taken by a packet traveling across the IP (Internet Protocol) network. It also shows the IP addresses of all the routers moving from the source to the destination.\nUses: \nIt shows the time taken by the packet for each hop during the transmission, where hop is the move our data makes to go from one point to another.\nWhen the packet is lost during the transmission, the traceroute will identify the point of failure. This is done by receiving an ICMP time exceeded message from the hop, which tells us that the time-to-live value of that packet has reached zero.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "17. What is a three-way handshake?",
        "answer": "A three-way handshake is a term given to the process of making the connection between a local host and the server in a TCP/IP network. As the name suggests, it is a three-way process where a reliable connection is set up between 2 devices with synchronization (SYN)  and acknowledgment (ACK) before sharing of data. \nStep 1: The client first sends a synchronization (SYN) to the server to make the connection.\nStep 2: The server then responds to the client’s request with synchronization (SYN) and acknowledgment (ACK).\nStep 3: The client sends back an acknowledgment (ACK) to the server’s response, telling that the connection was established.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "18. What is data leakage?",
        "answer": "Data leakage is when unauthorized information about a business is sent to a third party via the internet, mobile data, email, USK keys, laptops, etc.\nTypes of data leakage:\nAccidental leakage: As the name suggests, this is when an authorized person accidentally sends the information to an unauthorized person. \nMalicious insiders: This is when an authorized person sends data to an unauthorized person intentionally.\nElectronic communication: This is when a hacker uses different hacking tools to enter the system.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "19. Explain brute force attacks and the ways to prevent them.",
        "answer": "This is an attack where the attacker tries to guess the password with trial and error. This is done with the help of software used to log in with credentials. \nHere are some ways to prevent a brute force attack:\nSet a lengthy password\nSet a high-complexity password\nSet a limit for login failures",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "20. Explain port scanning.",
        "answer": "A port scan helps to check for open ports, listening, or closed on a network. This is used by administrators to check for network security and the system’s firewall strength. This is a popular exploration tool to identify the weak point in the system to break in.\nSome of the common basic port scanning techniques are:\nUDP\nPing scan\nTCP connect\nTCP half-open\nStealth scanning",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "21. Distinguish between HIDS and NIDS.",
        "answer": "Host Intrusion Detection System Network Intrusion Detection System\nDetects the attacks that involve hosts Detects attacks that involve networks \nAnalyzes what a particular host/application is doing Examines the network traffic of all devices\nDiscovers hackers only after the machine is breached Discovers hackers at the time they generate unauthorized attacks",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "22. Mention the difference between symmetric and asymmetric encryption.",
        "answer": "Differentiator  Symmetric Encryption Asymmetric Encryption\nEncryption Key Only one key to encrypt and decrypt a message Two different keys (public and private keys) to encrypt and decrypt the message\nSpeed of Execution Encryption is faster and simple Encryption is slower and complicated\nAlgorithms RC4, AES, DES, and 3DES RSA, Diffie-Hellman, and ECC\nUsage  For the transmission of large chunks of data For smaller transmission to establish a secure connection prior to the actual data transfer",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "23. What is the difference between IDS and IPS?",
        "answer": "Intrusion Detection System Intrusion Prevention System\nA network infrastructure to detect intrusion by hackers A network infrastructure to prevent intrusions by hackers\nFlags invasion as threads Denies the malicious traffic from threads\nDetects port scanners, malware, and other violations Does not deliver malicious packets if the traffic is from known threats in databases",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "24. What are the different layers of the OSI model?",
        "answer": "The OSI model was introduced by the International Organization for Standardization for different computer systems to communicate with each other using standard protocols.\n\nBelow are the various layers of the OSI model:\nPhysical layer: This layer allows the transmission of raw data bits over a physical medium.\nData Link layer: This layer determines the format of the data in the network.\nNetwork layer: It tells which path the data will take.\nTransport layer: This layer allows the transmission of data using TCP/UDP protocols.\nSession layer: It controls sessions and ports to maintain the connections in the network.\nPresentation layer: Data encryptions happen in this layer, and it ensures that the data is in a usable/presentable format.\nApplication layer: This is where the user interacts with the application.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "25. What is a VPN?",
        "answer": "Your online activities are protected from the risks of a public internet connection by a virtual private network, or VPN, which establishes a private and secure network. You may protect tasks like sending emails, making online payments, and conducting e-commerce by utilizing a VPN to increase your anonymity and privacy.\nWorking of VPN\nWhen you make a VPN connection, your device routes the internet connection to the VPN’s private server, instead of your Internet Service Provider (ISP). \nDuring this transmission, your data is encrypted and sent through another point on the internet.\nWhen it reaches the server, the data is decrypted.\nThe response from the server reaches the VPN where it is encrypted, and it will be decrypted by another point in the VPN.\nAt last, the data, which is decrypted, reaches you.\nAre you excited to know about the Access Control List, so check out this blog!",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "26. What do you understand by risk, vulnerability, and threat in a network?",
        "answer": "A cyber security threat possesses the potential to harm an organization’s assets by exploiting vulnerabilities, whether intentional or accidental.\nA vulnerability represents a security system weakness or gap that can be exploited by malicious hackers.\nRisk emerges when a threat successfully exploits a vulnerability, leading to loss, destruction, or damage to assets.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "27. How do you prevent identity theft?",
        "answer": "To prevent identity theft, you can take the following measures:\nProtect your personal records.\nAvoid online sharing of confidential information.\nProtect your AADHAR/Social Security Number.\nUse strong passwords, and change them at regular intervals.\nDo not provide your bank information on untrustworthy websites.\nProtect your system with advanced firewall and spyware tools.\nKeep your browsers, system, and software updated.\nEnroll in our Cyber Security Course in Bangalore to upskill yourself!",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "28. Who are White Hat, Grey Hat, and Black Hat Hackers?",
        "answer": "Black Hat Hackers\nA black hat hacker uses his/her hacking skills to breach confidential data without permission. With the obtained data, the individual performs malicious activities such as injecting malware, viruses, and worms.\nWhite Hat Hackers\nA white hat hacker uses his/her hacking skills to break into a system but with the permission of the respective organizations. They are professionals known as Ethical Hackers. They hack the system to identify its vulnerability and to fix it before a hacker takes advantage of it.\nGrey Hat Hackers\nA grey hat hacker has the characteristics of both a black hat hacker and a white hat hacker. Here, the system is violated with no bad intention but they do not have the essential permission to surf the system, so it might become a potential threat at any time.\nCheck out this interesting blog on Cyber Security Consultant Career!",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "29. When should you do patch management, and how often?",
        "answer": "Immediate action is required to perform patch management as soon as software updates are released. It is crucial that all network devices within the organization undergo patch management within a timeframe of one month or less.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "30. What are the ways to reset a password-protected BIOS configuration?",
        "answer": "BIOS being hardware, setting it up with a password locks the operating system. There are three ways to reset the BIOS password:\n you need to unplug the PC and remove the CMOS battery in the cabinet for 15–30 minutes. Then, you can put it back.\nYou can use third-party software such as CmosPwd and Kiosk.\nYou can run the below commands from the MS-DOS prompt with the help of the debug tool. For this method to work, you need to have access to the OS installed.\nDebug\no 70 2E\no 71 FF\nquit\nThis will reset all BIOS configurations, and you will need to re-enter the settings for it.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "31. Explain the MITM attack. How to prevent it?",
        "answer": "In the Man-in-the-Middle attack, the hacker eavesdrops on the communication between two parties. The individual then impersonates another person and makes the data transmission look normal for the other parties. The intent is to alter the data, steal personal information, or get login credentials for sabotaging communication.\nThese are a few ways to prevent a MITM attack:\nPublic key pair based authentication\nVirtual private network\nStrong router login credentials\nImplement a well-built Intrusion Detection Systems (IDS) like firewalls. \nStrong WEP/WPA encryption on access points",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "32. Explain the DDoS attack. How to prevent it?",
        "answer": "Distributed denial-of-service attack overwhelms the target website, system, or network with huge traffic, more than the server’s capacity. The aim is to make the server/website inaccessible to its intended users. A DDoS attack happens in the below two ways:\nFlooding attacks: This is the most commonly occurring type of DDoS attack. Flooding attacks stop the system when the server is accumulated with massive amounts of traffic that it cannot handle. The attacker sends packets continuously with the help of automated software.\nCrash attacks: This is the least common DDoS attack where the attacker exploits a bug in the targeted system to cause a system crash. It prevents legitimate users from accessing email, websites, banking accounts, and gaming sites. \nTo prevent a DDoS attack, you have to:\nConfigure firewalls and routers\nRecognize the spike in traffic\nConsider front-end hardware \nEmpower the server with scalability and load balancing\nUse anti-DDoS software\nAlso, Read on: Intrusion Prevention System to enhance your Knowledge!",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "33. Explain the XSS attack. How to prevent it?",
        "answer": "Cross-site scripting also known as XSS attack allows the attacker to pretend as a victimised user to carry out the actions that the user can perform, in turn, stealing any of the user’s data. If the attacker can masquerade as a privileged victimised user, one can gain full control over all the application’s data and functionality. Here, the attacker injects malicious client-side code into web services to steal information, run destructive code, take control of a user’s session, and perform a phishing scam.\nHere are the ways to prevent an XSS attack:\nCross-check the user’s input\nSanitize HTML \nEmploy anti-XSS tools\nUse encoding \nCheck for regular updates of the software",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "34. What is an ARP, and how does it work?",
        "answer": "Address Resolution Protocol is a communication protocol of the network layer in the OSI model. Its function is to find the MAC address for the given IP address of the system. It converts the IPv4 address, which is 32-bit, into a 48-bit MAC address.\nHow ARP works:\nIt sends an ARP request that broadcasts frames to the entire network.\nAll nodes on the network receive the ARP request.\nThe nodes check whether the request matches with the ARP table to find the target’s MAC address.\nIf it does not match, then the nodes silently discard the packet.\nIf it matches, the target will send an ARP response back to the original sender via unicast.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "35. What is port blocking within LAN?",
        "answer": "Port blocking within LAN involves the act of preventing users from accessing a specific set of services within the local area network. The primary objective is to halt the source’s capability to grant access to destination nodes through ports. As all applications operate on ports, it becomes crucial to obstruct these ports in order to limit unauthorized access, which could potentially exploit security vulnerabilities within the network infrastructure.\n\nAdvanced Cyber Security Interview Questions and Answers",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "36. What are the protocols that fall under the TCP/IP Internet layer?",
        "answer": "Application Layer NFS, NIS, SNMP, telnet, ftp, rlogin, rsh, rcp, RIP, RDISC, DNS, LDAP, and others\nTransport Layer TCP, SCTP, UDP, etc.\nInternet IPv4, ARP, ICMP, IPv6, etc.\nData Link Layer IEEE 802.2, PPP, etc.\nPhysical Layer Ethernet (IEEE 802.3), FDDI, Token Ring, RS-232, and others",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "37. What is a botnet?",
        "answer": "A botnet, also called a robot network, is a malware that infects networks of computers and gets them under the control of a single attacker who is called a ‘bot herder.’ A bot is an individual machine that is under the control of bot herders. The attacker acts as a central party who can command every bot to perform simultaneous and coordinated criminal actions.\nA botnet is usually always responsible for large-scale attacks since a bot herder can control millions of bots at a time. All the bot can receive updates from the attacker to change their behavior in no time.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "38. What is a CSRF attack? How is it executed?",
        "answer": "Cross-Site Request Forgery (CSRF) attack, also known as session riding or one-click attack, is a malicious exploit that tricks a victim into performing unintended actions on a website on which they are authenticated. It occurs when an attacker exploits the trust between a user’s browser and a targeted website. The attack takes advantage of the fact that websites often rely on cookies or other authentication credentials to verify a user’s identity.\nIn order to execute a CSRF attack, an attacker typically follows these steps:\nIdentify the Target: The attacker selects a target website or web application that has a vulnerability that can be exploited through CSRF.\nCraft the Malicious Payload: The attacker creates a malicious payload, typically in the form of HTML or JavaScript code, which will be executed by the victim’s browser.\nCreate a Malicious Website: The attacker sets up a malicious website or incorporates the malicious payload into a legitimate website that they control. This website will be used to trick the victim into unknowingly performing actions on the target website.\nExploit the Trust Relationship: The attacker entices the victim to visit the malicious website. This can be done through social engineering techniques such as sending phishing emails, distributing malicious advertisements, or leveraging cross-site scripting (XSS) vulnerabilities.\nVictim Interaction: When the victim visits the malicious website, the malicious payload is executed in their browser without their knowledge. The payload contains requests designed to mimic legitimate actions on the target website.\nSending Forged Requests: The victim’s browser automatically sends HTTP requests to the target website, carrying out actions on behalf of the victim. These requests can include changing account settings, making purchases, or performing any action that the victim’s account is authorized to do.\nExploiting Authentication: The target website receives the forged requests and processes them, assuming they are legitimate due to the victim’s authenticated session (e.g., session cookies) with the website. As a result, the actions requested by the attacker are performed on the victim’s behalf.\nAttack Success: If the CSRF attack is successful, the attacker achieves their desired outcome, which can range from unauthorized actions to data theft, depending on the vulnerability and the attacker’s intentions.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "39. What are salted hashes?",
        "answer": "When two users have the same password, it will result in the creation of the same password hashes. In such a case, an attacker can easily crack the password by performing a dictionary or brute-force attack. To avoid this, a salted hash is implemented.\nA salted hash is used to randomize hashes by prepending or appending a random string (salt) to the password before hashing. This results in the creation of two completely different hashes, which can be employed to protect the users’ passwords in the database against the attacker.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "40. What is ARP poisoning?",
        "answer": "Address Resolution Protocol (ARP) poisoning, also known as ARP spoofing or ARP cache poisoning, is a type of cyber attack where an attacker manipulates the ARP tables on a local area network (LAN). The attack involves sending falsified ARP messages to associate the attacker’s MAC address with the IP address of another device on the network, redirecting network traffic intended for that device to the attacker.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "41. Explain SSL and TLS.",
        "answer": "Secure Sockets Layer (SSL)\nIt employs encryption algorithms to keep any sensitive data that is sent between a client and a server by scrambling the data in transit. This helps prevent hackers from reading any data, such as credit card details and personal and other financial information; it is done by keeping the internet connection secure.\nTransport Layer Security (TLS)\nTLS is the successor of SSL. It is an improved protocol version that works just like SSL to protect information transfer. However, to provide better security, both TLS and SSL are often implemented together.\nStay one step ahead: Enhance your knowledge of application security and proactively mitigate risks in your software!",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "42. What is data protection in transit vs data protection at rest?",
        "answer": "Data Protection in Transit Data Protection at Rest\nData is transmitted across devices or networks Data is stored in databases, local hard drives, or USBs\nProtects the data in transit with SSL and TLS Protects the data at rest with firewalls, antiviruses, and good security practices \nYou must protect the data in transit since it can become vulnerable to MITM attacks, eavesdropping, etc.  You should protect the data at rest to avoid possible data breaches even when stolen or downloaded",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "43. What is 2FA, and how can it be implemented for public websites?",
        "answer": "Two-factor authentication (2FA) requires a password, along with a unique form of identification like a login code via text message (SMS) or a mobile application, to verify a user. When the user enters the password, they are prompted to enter the security code to log in to the website. If the code mismatches, the user will be blocked from entering the website.\nExamples of 2FA: Google Authenticator, YubiKey, Microsoft Authenticator, etc.\nLet’s get a dive into the Cyber Security Interview Questions for Freshers.\n\nCyber Security Interview Questions for Freshers",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "44. Differentiate between hashing and encryption.",
        "answer": "Hashing Encryption\nA one-way function where you cannot decrypt the original message Encrypted data can be decrypted to the original text with a proper key\nUsed to verify data Used to transmit data securely\nUsed to send files, passwords, etc. and to search Used to transfer sensitive business information\nLooking for a rewarding career in ethical hacking? Enroll in our Ethical Hacking course and pave the way for success!",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "45. What is the difference between vulnerability assessment (VA) and penetration testing (PT)?",
        "answer": "Vulnerability Assessment (VA) Penetration Testing (PT)\nIdentifies the vulnerabilities in a network Identifies vulnerabilities to exploit them to penetrate the system\nTells how susceptible the network is Tells whether the detected vulnerability is genuine\nConducted at regular intervals when there is a change in the system or network Conducted annually when there are significant changes introduced into the system",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "46. What is SSL encryption?",
        "answer": "The Secure Socket Layer (SSL) functions as a security protocol utilized for encryption, enabling network privacy, data integrity, and authentication, particularly in scenarios like online transactions.\nTo establish SSL encryption, the following steps are undertaken in an active tone:\nThe browser initiates a connection with an SSL-secured web server.\nThe browser requests the server’s public key while providing its own private key.\nUpon confirming the server’s trustworthiness, the browser proceeds to establish an encrypted connection with the web server.\nThe web server acknowledges the request and commences an SSL-encrypted connection.\nSSL communication takes place between the browser and the web server.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "47. Define a zero-day vulnerability.",
        "answer": "A zero-day vulnerability refers to a security flaw or weakness in a software application or system that is unknown to the vendor or developers, leaving it exposed to potential exploitation by attackers. The term “zero-day” implies that the vulnerability is discovered and exploited by hackers before the software vendor becomes aware of it, giving them zero days to address and patch the vulnerability. As a result, no official fixes or countermeasures are available to protect against such attacks.\nSome examples of zero-day vulnerabilities are the following:\nStuxnet Worm in 2010\nPetya Ransomware in 2016\nAdobe Flash Player in 2015",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "48. With the differential parameters, differentiate between HTTP and HTTPS.",
        "answer": "Below mentioned are the differences between HTTP and HTTPS protocols:\nParameters HTTP (Hypertext Transfer Protocol) HTTPS (Hypertext Transfer Protocol Secure)\nProtocol Type Unsecured Secured\nEncryption No encryption SSL/TLS encryption\nPort Port 80 Port 443\nData Security Data is sent in plain text. Data is encrypted before transmission.\nAuthentication No built-in authentication mechanism Utilizes SSL/TLS certificates for authentication\nURL Scheme Begins with “http://” Begins with “https://”\nSecurity Risk Prone to eavesdropping and data interception Protects against eavesdropping and data interception",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "49. What countermeasures will you take to secure a server?",
        "answer": "A server that is secured uses the Secure Socket Layer (SSL) protocol to encrypt and decrypt data to protect it from unauthorized access.\nBelow are the four steps to secure a server:\nStep 1: Secure the root and administrator users with a password\nStep 2: Create new users who will manage the system\nStep 3: Do not give remote access to administrator/default root accounts\nStep 4: Configure firewall rules for remote access\n\nCyber Interview Questions for Experienced",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "50. What do you mean by Cognitive Cybersecurity?",
        "answer": "Cognitive Cybersecurity is a way of using human-like thought mechanisms and converting them to be used by Artificial Intelligence technologies in cyber security to detect security threats. It is to impart human knowledge to the cognitive system, which will be able to serve as a self-learning system. This helps identify the threats, determine their impact, and manifest reactive strategies.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "51. What is the difference between VPN and VLAN?",
        "answer": "Virtual Private Network  Virtual Local Area Network \nProvides secure remote access to a company’s network resources  Used to group multiple computers that are geographically in different domains into the same geographical broadcast domain\nA network service A way of subnetting the network\nCompanies wishing to connect with their remote employees will use a VPN Companies wishing to employ traffic control and easier management will use a VLAN",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "52. Explain phishing and how you prevent it.",
        "answer": "In phishing, an attacker masquerades as a trusted entity (a legitimate person/company) to obtain sensitive information by manipulating the victim. It is achieved by any kind of user interaction, such as asking the victim to click on a malicious link and to download a risky attachment, to get confidential information such as credit card information, usernames, passwords, and network credentials. \nThe following are some of the ways to prevent phishing:\nInstall firewalls\nRotate passwords frequently\nDo not click on or download from unknown sources\nGet free anti-phishing tools\nDo not provide your personal information on an unsecured/unknown site",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "53. Explain SQL injection. How can we prevent it?",
        "answer": "SQL injection is an injection attack where an attacker executes malicious SQL commands on the database server, including MySQL, SQL Server, or Oracle, that runs behind a web application. The intent is to gain unauthorized access to sensitive data such as client information, personal information, intellectual property details, and so on. In this attack, the attacker can add, modify, and delete records in the database, which results in the loss of data integrity in an organization.\nWays to prevent SQL injection:\nLimit providing read access to the database\nSanitize data with the limitation of special characters\nValidate user inputs\nUse prepared statements\nCheck for active updates and patches",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "54. Mention the steps used for configuring a firewall.",
        "answer": "The steps mentioned below need to be followed to set up a password:\nUsername/password: Alter the default password of a firewall device.\nRemote Administration: Always disable the Remote Administration feature.\nPort Forward: For the web server, FTP, and other applications to work properly, configure appropriate ports.\nDHCP Server: Disable the DHCP server when you install a firewall to avoid conflicts.\nLogging: Enable logs to view the firewall troubleshoots and to view logs.\nPolicies: Configure strong security policies with the firewall.\nWant to know How to become a cyber security engineer in 2024? check this blog out!",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "55. Explain phishing and how do you prevent it?",
        "answer": "In phishing, an attacker masquerades as a trusted entity (as a legitimate person/company) to obtain sensitive information by manipulating the victim. It is achieved by any kind of user interaction, such as asking the victim to click on a malicious link and to download a risky attachment, to get confidential information such as credit card information, usernames, passwords, and network credentials. \nThe following are some of the ways to prevent phishing:\nInstall firewalls\nRotate passwords frequently\nDo not click on or download from unknown sources\nGet free anti-phishing tools\nDo not provide your personal information on an unsecured/unknown site",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "56. Explain SQL injection. How to prevent it?",
        "answer": "SQL injection is an injection attack where an attacker executes malicious SQL commands in the database server, including MySQL, SQL Server, or Oracle, that runs behind a web application. The intent is to gain unauthorized access to sensitive data such as client information, personal information, intellectual property details, and so on. In this attack, the attacker can add, modify, and delete records in the database, which results in the loss of data integrity in an organization.\nWays to prevent SQL injection:\nLimit providing read access to the database\nSanitize data with the limitation of special characters\nValidate user inputs\nUse prepared statements\nCheck for active updates and patches\nHave a look at this Cyber Security Tutorial, which will make it easier for you to dive into this field!\n\nScenario-based Cyber Security Interview Questions and Answers",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "57. You have a suture from where you receive the following email from the help desk:",
        "answer": "Dear YYY,\nWe are deleting all inactive emails to create space for other new users. If you want to save your account data, please provide the following details: First Name and Last Name:\nEmail ID:\nPassword:\nDate of Birth:\nAlternate Email: Please submit the above detail by the end of the week to avoid any account termination.\nThe above email is an excellent illustration of phishing. Here are the reasons why:\nA reputed organization will never ask for an employee’s personal information in the mail.\nIn a normal mail, the salutation is not done in a generalized manner. This happens only in spam emails where the attacker tricks you into ‘biting.’\nAs a rule of thumb, you should never revert to a sender who demands personal information and passwords via emails, phone calls, text messages, and instant messages (IMs). You must not disclose your data to any external party even if the sender works for organizations such as ITS or UCSC.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "58. You get an e-card in your mail from a friend. It asks you to download an attachment to view the card. What will you do? Justify your answer.",
        "answer": "Do not download the attachment as it may have viruses, malware, or bugs, which might corrupt your system.\nDo not visit any links as they might redirect you to an unintended page.\nAs fake email addresses are common and easy to create, you should not perform any action like clicking/downloading any links, unless you confirm it with the actual person.\nMany websites masquerade as legitimate sites to steal sensitive information, so you should be careful not to fall into the wrong hands.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "59. A staff member in a company subscribes to various free magazines. To activate the subscription, the first magazine asks her for her birth month, the second magazine asks for her birth year, and the third magazine asks for her maiden name. What do you deduce from the above situation? Justify your answer.",
        "answer": "It is highly likely that the above-mentioned three newsletters are from a parent company, which are distributed through different channels. It can be used to gather essential pieces of information that might look safe in the user’s eyes. However, this can be misused to sell personal information to carry out identity theft. It might further ask the user for the date of birth for the activation of the fourth newsletter.\nIn many scenarios, questions that involve personal details are unnecessary, and you should not provide them to any random person, company, or website unless it is for a legitimate purpose.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "60. Case study:In our computing labs and departments, the print billing system is typically linked to the user's login. Users log in, initiate print jobs, and subsequently receive a bill for the printed material, either individually or through their respective departments. Occasionally, individuals contact us to express their dissatisfaction with invoices for printing they claim they did not perform, only to discover that the bills are, in fact, accurate. Question: What do you believe could be the underlying issue in this situation?",
        "answer": "To avoid this situation, you should always sign out of all accounts, close the browser, and quit the programs when you use a shared or public computer. There are chances that an illegitimate user can retrieve your authorized data and perform actions on behalf of you without your knowledge when you keep the accounts in a logged-in state.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "61. What is DMZ in cybersecurity?",
        "answer": "DMZ stands for demilitarized zone. It is a network architecture that acts as a buffer zone between an organization’s internal network and an external or untrusted network, typically the internet. The purpose of a DMZ is to provide an additional layer of security by segregating and isolating certain systems or services that need to be accessible from the internet.\nThe DMZ is designed to host publicly accessible services such as web servers, email servers, or FTP servers that need to be accessed by users outside the organization. Placing these services in the DMZ separates them from the internal network, reducing the potential attack surface and minimizing the risk to sensitive resources and data. A DMZ is implemented using firewalls and network segmentation techniques. \nTypically, two firewalls are employed: one facing the internet and another separating the DMZ from the internal network. The external-facing firewall allows limited and controlled inbound traffic to reach the DMZ, while the internal-facing firewall enforces strict rules to prevent unauthorized access from the DMZ to the internal network.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "62. Differentiate between DDoS and DoS attack.",
        "answer": "Parameters DDoS Attack  DoS Attack\nAttack Method DDoS attacks involve multiple sources, often compromised computers or devices forming a botnet. These sources collectively bombard the target with a massive volume of traffic or requests, making it difficult to mitigate the attack. A single source or a small group of sources flood the target system or network with a high volume of traffic or requests, overwhelming its resources and causing service disruption or denial.\nSource of Attack DDoS attacks utilize a distributed network of compromised devices, making it harder to identify and mitigate the attack. The sources are often geographically dispersed. A DoS attack typically originates from a single source or a limited number of sources under the attacker’s control.\nScale and Impact DDoS attacks can generate an enormous volume of traffic, overwhelming even robust systems or networks. They have a larger scale and can lead to significant downtime, rendering services completely inaccessible. Due to the limited resources of a single source or a few sources, a DoS attack generally has a smaller scale and impact. It may cause a temporary disruption or slowdown of services.\nComplexity and Coordination DDoS attacks demand more resources, planning, and coordination to compromise multiple devices and coordinate the attack. They involve exploiting vulnerabilities and establishing control over a network of compromised machines. Implementing a DoS attack requires less coordination and resources. It can be launched by an individual or a small group using readily available tools or scripts.\nDetection and Mitigation DDoS attacks are more challenging to detect and mitigate due to the distributed nature of the attack traffic. Advanced DDoS mitigation solutions are required, involving traffic analysis, rate limiting, or employing cloud-based DDoS protection services. Detecting and mitigating DoS attacks is relatively straightforward since the attack traffic often originates from a single or a few sources. Filtering or blocking the source IP addresses can help mitigate the attack.\nMotivation DDoS attacks can have similar motivations as DoS attacks, but they are more frequently associated with organized crime, hacktivism, or state-sponsored actors attempting to cause widespread disruption or target specific organizations or infrastructure. DoS attacks are often carried out by individuals or groups seeking to disrupt services, gain a competitive advantage, or settle personal grudges.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "63. Case study: In your college computer lab, one of your friends logged into her email account. When she left the lab, she only logged out from her email account. Later, she received a notification that someone had re-accessed her account from the college computer system’s browser, which she has used to send emails. Question- How do you think this happened?",
        "answer": "There are two possible scenarios:\nThe attacker can visit the browser’s history to access her account if she hasn’t logged out.\nEven if she has logged out but has not cleared the web cache (pages a browser saves to gain easy and quick access for the future)",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "64. Case study: An employee’s bank account faces an error during a direct deposit procedure. Two different offices need to work on it to straighten this out. Office #1 contacts Office #2 by email to send the valid account information for the deposit. The employee now gives the bank confirmation that the error no longer exists. Question- What is wrong here?",
        "answer": "Any sensitive information cannot be shared via email as it can lead to identity theft. This is because emails are mostly not private and secure. Sharing or sending personal information along the network is not recommended as the route can be easily tracked.\nIn such scenarios, the involved parties should call each other and work with ITS as a secure way of sending the information.\nCheck out this interesting blog on the difference between Cyber Security and Information Security!",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "65. You see an unusual activity of the mouse pointer, which starts to move around on its own and clicks on various things on the desktop. What should you do in this situation?",
        "answer": "A. Call any of the co-workers to seek help\nB. Disconnect the mouse\nC. Turn your computer off\nD. Inform the supervisor\nE. Disconnect your computer from the network\nF. Run anti-virus\nG. Select all the options that apply?\nWhich options would you choose?\nThe answer is (D) and (E). This kind of activity is surely suspicious as an unknown authority seems to have the access to control the computer remotely. In such cases, you should immediately report it to the respective supervisor. You can keep the computer disconnected from the network till help arrives.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "66. Check out the list of passwords below, which are pulled out from a database and choose the passwords that are in line with the UCSC’s password requirements:",
        "answer": "A. Password1\nB. @#$)*&^%\nC. UcSc4Evr!\nD. akHGksmLN\nChoose the passwords that are in line with the UCSC’s password requirements.\nThe answer is C (UcSc4Evr!). As per the UCSC requirements, a password should be:\nMinimum of 8 characters in length\nHaving any of the three from these four types of characters: lower case, upper case, numbers, and special characters.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "67. The bank sends you an email, which says it has encountered a problem with your account. The email is provided with instructions and also a link to log in to the account so that you can fix it. What do you infer from the above situation? Explain.",
        "answer": "It appears to be an unsolicited email. You should report it as spam and move the email to the trash immediately in the respective web client you use (Yahoo Mail, Gmail, etc.). Before providing any bank-related credentials online, you should call the bank to check if the message is legitimate and is from the bank.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "68. In your IT company, employees are registering numerous complaints that the campus computers are delivering Viagra spam. To verify it, you check the reports, and it turns out to be correct. The computer program is automatically sending tons of spam emails without the owner’s knowledge. This happened because a hacker had installed a malicious program into the system. What are the reasons you think might have caused this incident?",
        "answer": "This type of attack happens when the password is hacked. To avoid this, whenever you set a password, always use a proper standard, i.e., use passwords that are at least 8-character length and have a combination of upper case/lower case letters, symbols/special characters, and numbers.\nOther scenarios of the above attack could be:\nDated antivirus software or the lack of it \nDated updates or security patches\nThat’s all for now!\nThis blog has listed answers to the most frequently asked Cyber Security analyst interview questions. The answers provided here aim to help you have an understanding of Cyber Security basics. You have also understood how you can implement the concepts practically in the real world through scenario-based questions. Hope this will help you crack your next Cybersecurity interview.\n\nDownload the Cyber Security Interview Questions and Answers PDF to prepare for interviews offline.\nCyber Security Salary Trends",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "69. You've been notified of a potential ransomware attack on your network. What are your immediate steps to contain the damage and mitigate the attack?",
        "answer": "Here are some immediate steps to contain the damage and mitigate the attack:\nIsolate infected systems: Immediately disconnect affected devices from the network to prevent further spread.\nIdentify the payload and entry point: Investigate the ransomware strain and analyze logs to pinpoint the attack vector.\nAssess data impacted: Determine what data was encrypted and if backups are available for restoring critical information.\nNotify stakeholders: Inform key personnel and authorities according to your incident response plan.\nPrepare for recovery: If restoring from backups is feasible, ensure their validity and initiate the restoration process.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "70. You suspect a coworker might be accessing unauthorized data. What are your initial steps to investigate and address the situation?",
        "answer": "The initial steps to investigate and address the situation are as follows:\nDocument your observations: Note specific behaviors, data accessed, and timestamps without directly accusing the individual.\nReport your concerns to your supervisor or designated security personnel: Follow established internal reporting procedures.\nCooperate with the investigation: Offer any relevant information and assist with collecting evidence ethically and discreetly.\nMaintain confidentiality: Avoid discussing the situation with others before official inquiries conclude.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "71. You receive a suspicious email claiming to be from a vendor you regularly work with. How would you determine its legitimacy and avoid falling victim to a phishing attack?",
        "answer": "Here are some ideas to determine its legitimacy and avoid falling victim to a phishing attack:\nVerify sender details: Check the email address and domain name for inconsistencies with the vendor’s usual communication.\nHover over links without clicking: Preview links to see if they redirect to the expected vendor website.\nContact the vendor directly: Use trusted phone numbers or websites to confirm the email’s authenticity.\nReport the attempt: Report the suspicious email to your IT security team for further investigation.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "72. You detect unusual activity on your company's cloud storage platform. How do you identify and respond to the potential security incident?",
        "answer": "The following steps will help identify and respond to the potential security incident:\nAnalyze logs and audit trails: Identify the nature of the activity, affected files, and potential access points.\nUtilize cloud security tools: Leverage platform-specific features for threat detection, isolation, and investigation.\nEngage cloud security support: Collaborate with the cloud provider’s security team for advanced analysis and remediation.\nNotify internal stakeholders: Inform relevant teams about the incident and keep them updated on the response progress",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "73. Your company website experiences a sudden surge in traffic, potentially indicating a DoS attack. What are your initial steps to mitigate the impact?",
        "answer": "The initial steps to mitigate the impact are:\nIdentify the attack type and source: Utilize security tools to analyze traffic patterns and identify the attackers.\nActivate mitigation strategies: Implement pre-configured DoS protection measures or seek assistance from your security provider.\nCommunicate with users: Inform customers and stakeholders about the attack and any potential service disruptions.\nAnalyze and improve incident response: Evaluate the attack methods and update your defense strategies for future prevention.\n\nMCQs on Cyber Security",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "74. What is the difference between a virus and a worm?",
        "answer": "A. Viruses need a host program to run, while worms can replicate on their own.\nB. Worms are always more destructive than viruses.\nC. Viruses are always written in assembly language, while worms are written in higher-level languages.\nD. There is no difference between a virus and a worm.\nViruses need a host program to run, while worms can replicate on their own.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "75. What is a denial-of-service (DoS) attack?",
        "answer": "A. A type of attack that tries to steal data\nB. A type of attack that tries to crash a website or system\nC. A type of attack that tries to trick users into revealing personal information\nD. A type of attack that tries to encrypt data\nA type of attack that tries to crash a website or system. A DoS attack floods a website or system with traffic, making it unavailable to legitimate users.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "76. What is the primary function of an intrusion detection system (IDS)?",
        "answer": "A. To prevent unauthorized access to computer systems.\nB. To detect and monitor suspicious activity within a network or system.\nC. To encrypt data and protect it from unauthorized decryption.\nD. To back up data and restore it in case of a cyberattack.\nAn IDS monitors network traffic and system activity for signs of malicious behavior, alerting security personnel to potential threats.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "77. What is the most effective way to protect yourself from social engineering attacks like phishing?",
        "answer": "A. Install antivirus software and keep it updated.\nB. Be cautious about clicking on links or opening attachments in emails, even from seemingly familiar senders.\nC. Never share your personal information online, even on social media.\nD. All of the above.\nAll of the above. Maintaining vigilance, being cautious with links and attachments, and protecting personal information are crucial for avoiding social engineering traps.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "78. Which cryptographic algorithm provides the highest level of security for data at rest, making it suitable for highly sensitive information?",
        "answer": "A. AES-256\nB. RSA-2048\nC. SHA-256\nD. MD5\nRSA-2048 (Image of RSA-2048 encryption)",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "1. What do you mean by a Null Session?",
        "answer": "A null session occurs when a user is not authorized using either a username or a password. It can provide a security concern for apps because it implies that the person making the request is unknown.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "2. Differentiate between threat, vulnerability and risk.",
        "answer": "Threat: A threat is any form of hazard that has the potential to destroy or steal data, disrupt operations, or cause harm in general. Malware, phishing, data breaches, and even unethical employees are all examples of threats.\nThreat actors, who might be individuals or groups with a variety of backgrounds and motives, express threats. Understanding threats is essential for developing effective mitigations and making informed cybersecurity decisions. Threat intelligence is information regarding threats and threat actors. Threat:  Vulnerability: A vulnerability is a flaw in hardware, software, personnel, or procedures that threat actors can use to achieve their objectives.\nPhysical vulnerabilities, such as publicly exposed networking equipment, software vulnerabilities, such as a buffer overflow vulnerability in a browser, and even human vulnerabilities, such as an employee vulnerable to phishing assaults, are all examples of vulnerabilities.\nVulnerability management is the process of identifying, reporting and repairing vulnerabilities. A zero-day vulnerability is a vulnerability for which a remedy is not yet available. Vulnerability:   Risk: The probability of a threat and the consequence of a vulnerability are combined to form risk. To put it another way, the risk is the likelihood of a threat agent successfully exploiting a vulnerability, which may be calculated using the formula: Risk: Risk = Likelihood of a threat * Vulnerability Impact Risk = Likelihood of a threat * Vulnerability Impact Risk management is the process of identifying all potential hazards, analyzing their impact, and determining the best course of action. It's a never-ending procedure that examines new threats and vulnerabilities on a regular basis. Risks can be avoided, minimized, accepted, or passed to a third party depending on the response chosen.  ",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "3. What does XSS stand for? How can it be prevented?",
        "answer": "XSS stands for Cross-site scripting. It is a web security flaw that allows an attacker to manipulate how users interact with a susceptible application. It allows an attacker to get around the same-origin policy, which is meant to keep websites separate from one another. Cross-site scripting flaws allow an attacker to impersonate a victim user and execute any actions that the user is capable of, as well as access any of the user's data. If the victim user has privileged access to the application, the attacker may be able to take complete control of the app's functionality and data.   Preventing cross-site scripting can be simple in some circumstances, but it can be much more difficult in others, depending on the application's sophistication and how it handles user-controllable data. In general, preventing XSS vulnerabilities will almost certainly need a mix of the following measures:\nOn arrival, filter the input. Filter user input as precisely as feasible at the point when it is received, based on what is expected or valid input.\nOn the output, encode the data. Encode user-controllable data in HTTP responses at the point where it is output to avoid it being perceived as active content. Depending on the output context, a combination of HTML, URL, JavaScript, and CSS encoding may be required.\nUse headers that are relevant for the response. You can use the Content-Type and X-Content-Type-Options headers to ensure that browsers read HTTP responses in the way you intend, preventing XSS in HTTP responses that aren't intended to contain any HTML or JavaScript.\nPolicy for Content Security. You can utilize Content Security Policy (CSP) as a last line of defense to mitigate the severity of any remaining XSS issues.  On arrival, filter the input.  On the output, encode the data.  Use headers that are relevant for the response.  Policy for Content Security.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "4. What is a Firewall?",
        "answer": "A firewall serves as a barrier between a LAN and the Internet. It allows private resources to remain private while reducing security threats. It manages both inbound and outbound network traffic. A sample firewall between a LAN and the internet is shown in the diagram below. The point of vulnerability is the connection between the two. At this point, network traffic can be filtered using both hardware and software.   There are two types of firewall systems: one that uses network layer filters and the other that uses user, application, or network layer proxy servers.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "5. Define VPN.",
        "answer": "The term VPN refers to a virtual private network. It enables you to connect your computer to a private network, establishing an encrypted connection that hides your IP address, allowing you to safely share data and access the web while safeguarding your online identity. A virtual private network, or VPN, is an encrypted link between a device and a network via the Internet. The encrypted connection aids in the secure transmission of sensitive data. It protects against illegal eavesdropping on the traffic and allows the user to work remotely. In corporate settings, VPN technology is commonly used.  ",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "6. Who are Black Hat, White Hat and Grey Hat Hackers?",
        "answer": "Black Hat hackers, sometimes known as crackers, attempt to obtain unauthorized access to a system in order to disrupt its operations or steal critical data. Black Hat hackers Because of its malicious aim, black hat hacking is always illegal, including stealing company data, violating the privacy, causing system damage, and blocking network connection, among other things. Ethical hackers are also referred to as White hat hackers. As part of penetration testing and vulnerability assessments, they never intend to harm a system; rather, they strive to uncover holes in a computer or network system.\nEthical hacking is not a crime and is one of the most difficult professions in the IT business. Many businesses hire ethical hackers to do penetration tests and vulnerability assessments. White hat hackers  Grey hat hackers combine elements of both black and white hat hacking. They act without malice, but for the sake of amusement, they exploit a security flaw in a computer system or network without the permission or knowledge of the owner.\nTheir goal is to draw the owners' attention to the flaw in the hope of receiving gratitude or a small reward. Grey hat hackers   ",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "7. What are the types of Cyber Security?",
        "answer": "The assets of every company are made up of a variety of various systems. These systems have a strong cybersecurity posture, which necessitates coordinated actions across the board. As a result, cybersecurity can be divided into the following sub-domains: Network security: It is the process of securing a computer network against unauthorized access, intruders, attacks, disruption, and misuse using hardware and software. This security aids in the protection of an organization's assets from both external and internal threats. Example: Using a Firewall.\nApplication security: It entails safeguarding software and devices against malicious attacks. This can be accomplished by regularly updating the apps to ensure that they are secure against threats. \nData security: It entails putting in place a strong data storage system that ensures data integrity and privacy while in storage and transport.\nIdentity management: It refers to the process of identifying each individual's level of access inside an organization. Example: Restricting access to data as per the job role of an individual in the company.\nOperational security: It entails analyzing and making decisions about how to handle and secure data assets. Example: Storing data in an encrypted form in the database.\nMobile security: It refers to the protection of organizational and personal data held on mobile devices such as cell phones, PCs, tablets, and other similar devices against a variety of hostile attacks. Unauthorized access, device loss or theft, malware, and other threats are examples of these dangers.\nCloud security: It refers to the safeguarding of data held in a digital environment or in cloud infrastructures for an organization. It employs a variety of cloud service providers, including AWS, Azure, Google, and others, to assure protection against a variety of threats. Network security:  Application security:  Data security:  Identity management:  Operational security:  Mobile security:  Cloud security:",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "8. What are the benefits of Cyber Security?",
        "answer": "The following are some of the advantages of putting cybersecurity in place and keeping it up to date: Businesses are protected from cyberattacks and data breaches.\nBoth data and network security are safeguarded.\nUnauthorized user access is kept to a minimum.\nThere is a quicker recovery time after a breach.\nProtection for end-users and endpoint devices.\nRegulatory compliance.\nOperational consistency.\nDevelopers, partners, consumers, stakeholders, and employees have a higher level of trust in the company's reputation. Businesses are protected from cyberattacks and data breaches. Both data and network security are safeguarded. Unauthorized user access is kept to a minimum. There is a quicker recovery time after a breach. Protection for end-users and endpoint devices. Regulatory compliance. Operational consistency. Developers, partners, consumers, stakeholders, and employees have a higher level of trust in the company's reputation.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "9. What do you mean by a botnet?",
        "answer": "A botnet is a collection of internet-connected devices, such as servers, PCs, and mobile phones, that are infected with malware and controlled by it.\nIt's used to steal data, send spam, launch distributed denial-of-service (DDoS) attacks, and more, as well as provide the user access to the device and its connection.   ",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "10. What do you mean by honeypots?",
        "answer": "Honeypots are attack targets that are set up to see how different attackers attempt exploits. Private firms and governments can utilize the same concept to evaluate their vulnerabilities, which is widely used in academic settings.  ",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "11. Differentiate between Vulnerability Assessment and Penetration Testing.",
        "answer": "Vulnerability assessment and penetration testing are two different phrases that both serve the same purpose: to secure the network environment.   Vulnerability Assessment is a process for defining, detecting, and prioritizing vulnerabilities in computer systems, network infrastructure, applications, and other systems, as well as providing the necessary information to the organization to correct the flaws.\nPenetration Testing is also known as ethical hacking or pen-testing. It's a method of identifying vulnerabilities in a network, system, application, or other systems in order to prevent attackers from exploiting them. It is most commonly used to supplement a web application firewall in the context of web application security (WAF).\nA vulnerability scan is similar to approaching a door and checking to see if it is unlocked before stopping. A penetration test goes a step further, not only checking to see if the door is unlocked but also opening the door and walking right in. Vulnerability Assessment  Penetration Testing ",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "12. What is the main objective of Cyber Security?",
        "answer": "The primary goal of cyber security is to protect data. To safeguard data from cyber-attacks, the security sector offers a triangle of three connected principles. The CIA trio is the name for this principle. The CIA model is intended to help organizations develop policies for their information security architecture. One or more of these principles has been broken when a security breach is discovered. Confidentiality, Integrity, and Availability are the three components of the CIA model. It's a security paradigm that guides individuals through many aspects of IT security. Let's take a closer look at each section.   Confidentiality: Confidentiality is the same as privacy in that it prevents unauthorized access to data. It entails ensuring that the data is only accessible to those who are authorized to use it, as well as restricting access to others. It keeps vital information from getting into the wrong hands. Data encryption is a great example of keeping information private.\nIntegrity: This principle assures that the data is genuine, correct, and safe from unwanted threat actors or unintentional user alteration. If any changes are made, precautions should be taken to protect sensitive data from corruption or loss, as well as to quickly recover from such an incident. Furthermore, it denotes that the source of information must be genuine.\nAvailability: This principle ensures that information is constantly available and helpful to those who have access to it. It ensures that system failures or cyber-attacks do not obstruct these accesses. Confidentiality:  Integrity:  Availability:",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "13. What are the common types of cyber security attacks?",
        "answer": "The common types of cyber security attacks are:- Malware \nCross-Site Scripting (XSS) \nDenial-of-Service (DoS)\nDomain Name System Attack\nMan-in-the-Middle Attacks \nSQL Injection Attack \nPhishing\nSession Hijacking\nBrute Force Malware Cross-Site Scripting (XSS) Denial-of-Service (DoS) Domain Name System Attack Man-in-the-Middle Attacks SQL Injection Attack Phishing Session Hijacking Brute Force",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "14. What do you mean by brute force in the context of Cyber Security?",
        "answer": "A brute force attack is a cryptographic assault that uses a trial-and-error approach to guess all potential combinations until the correct data is discovered. This exploit is commonly used by cybercriminals to gain personal information such as passwords, login credentials, encryption keys, and PINs. It is very easy for hackers to implement this.  ",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "15. What do you mean by Shoulder Surfing?",
        "answer": "Shoulder surfing is a form of physical assault that entails physically peering at people's screens while they type information in a semi-public space.  ",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "16. What do you mean by Phishing?",
        "answer": "Phishing is a sort of cybercrime in which the sender appears to be a legitimate entity such as PayPal, eBay, financial institutions, or friends and coworkers. They send an email, phone call, or text message to a target or target with a link to convince them to click on the link. This link will take users to a fake website where they will be asked to enter sensitive information such as personal information, banking and credit card information, social security numbers, usernames, and passwords. By clicking the link, malware will be installed on the target machines, allowing hackers to remotely control them.   You can protect yourself from phishing attacks by following these guidelines: Don't give out important information on websites you don't know.\nCheck the site's security.\nMake use of firewalls.\nUse Toolbar for Anti-Phishing Don't give out important information on websites you don't know. Check the site's security. Make use of firewalls. Use Toolbar for Anti-Phishing",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "17. Differentiate between hashing and encryption.",
        "answer": "Hashing Encryption\nIt is a method of converting data to a smaller fixed value known as the key, which is then used to represent the original data. It's the technique of securely encoding data such that only the authorized user with the key or password can get the original data; for everyone else, it seems to be rubbish.\nBy whatever method, the hash code or key cannot be reverted to the original information. It can only be mapped, and the hash code is compared; if the hash code is the same, the information is identical; otherwise, it is not. It is not possible to get the original data. If we know the encryption key and technique used for encryption, we can easily extract the original data.\nIn comparison to encryption, it is more secure. In comparison to hashing, it is less secure.\nThe goal of hashing is to index and retrieve data from a database. The procedure is really quick. Encryption transforms data in order to keep it hidden from others.\nThe hashed data is usually short and constant in length. It does not increase in size as the length of information increases. The length of the encrypted data is not defined. It expands as the amount of data grows longer.\nEg:- SHA256 algorithm Eg:- RSA, AES algorithm Hashing Encryption\nIt is a method of converting data to a smaller fixed value known as the key, which is then used to represent the original data. It's the technique of securely encoding data such that only the authorized user with the key or password can get the original data; for everyone else, it seems to be rubbish.\nBy whatever method, the hash code or key cannot be reverted to the original information. It can only be mapped, and the hash code is compared; if the hash code is the same, the information is identical; otherwise, it is not. It is not possible to get the original data. If we know the encryption key and technique used for encryption, we can easily extract the original data.\nIn comparison to encryption, it is more secure. In comparison to hashing, it is less secure.\nThe goal of hashing is to index and retrieve data from a database. The procedure is really quick. Encryption transforms data in order to keep it hidden from others.\nThe hashed data is usually short and constant in length. It does not increase in size as the length of information increases. The length of the encrypted data is not defined. It expands as the amount of data grows longer.\nEg:- SHA256 algorithm Eg:- RSA, AES algorithm Hashing Encryption Hashing Encryption Hashing Encryption It is a method of converting data to a smaller fixed value known as the key, which is then used to represent the original data. It's the technique of securely encoding data such that only the authorized user with the key or password can get the original data; for everyone else, it seems to be rubbish.\nBy whatever method, the hash code or key cannot be reverted to the original information. It can only be mapped, and the hash code is compared; if the hash code is the same, the information is identical; otherwise, it is not. It is not possible to get the original data. If we know the encryption key and technique used for encryption, we can easily extract the original data.\nIn comparison to encryption, it is more secure. In comparison to hashing, it is less secure.\nThe goal of hashing is to index and retrieve data from a database. The procedure is really quick. Encryption transforms data in order to keep it hidden from others.\nThe hashed data is usually short and constant in length. It does not increase in size as the length of information increases. The length of the encrypted data is not defined. It expands as the amount of data grows longer.\nEg:- SHA256 algorithm Eg:- RSA, AES algorithm It is a method of converting data to a smaller fixed value known as the key, which is then used to represent the original data. It's the technique of securely encoding data such that only the authorized user with the key or password can get the original data; for everyone else, it seems to be rubbish. It is a method of converting data to a smaller fixed value known as the key, which is then used to represent the original data. It's the technique of securely encoding data such that only the authorized user with the key or password can get the original data; for everyone else, it seems to be rubbish. By whatever method, the hash code or key cannot be reverted to the original information. It can only be mapped, and the hash code is compared; if the hash code is the same, the information is identical; otherwise, it is not. It is not possible to get the original data. If we know the encryption key and technique used for encryption, we can easily extract the original data. By whatever method, the hash code or key cannot be reverted to the original information. It can only be mapped, and the hash code is compared; if the hash code is the same, the information is identical; otherwise, it is not. It is not possible to get the original data. If we know the encryption key and technique used for encryption, we can easily extract the original data. In comparison to encryption, it is more secure. In comparison to hashing, it is less secure. In comparison to encryption, it is more secure. In comparison to hashing, it is less secure. The goal of hashing is to index and retrieve data from a database. The procedure is really quick. Encryption transforms data in order to keep it hidden from others. The goal of hashing is to index and retrieve data from a database. The procedure is really quick. Encryption transforms data in order to keep it hidden from others. The hashed data is usually short and constant in length. It does not increase in size as the length of information increases. The length of the encrypted data is not defined. It expands as the amount of data grows longer. The hashed data is usually short and constant in length. It does not increase in size as the length of information increases. The length of the encrypted data is not defined. It expands as the amount of data grows longer. Eg:- SHA256 algorithm Eg:- RSA, AES algorithm Eg:- SHA256 algorithm Eg:- RSA, AES algorithm       ",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "18. What do you mean by two-factor authentication?",
        "answer": "Two-factor authentication (2FA), often known as two-step verification or dual-factor authentication, is a security method in which users validate their identity using two independent authentication factors. This procedure is carried out in order to better protect the user's credentials as well as the resources that the user has access to. Single-factor authentication (SFA), in which the user gives only one factor — generally a password or passcode — provides a lower level of security than two-factor authentication (TFA). Since possessing the defendant's password alone is not enough to accomplish the authentication check, two-factor authentication adds an extra layer of security to the authentication process, making it more difficult for attackers to get access to a person's devices or online accounts. Two-factor authentication (2FA)  ",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "19. How can you avoid a brute force attack?",
        "answer": "There are a variety of techniques for stopping or preventing brute force attacks. A robust password policy is the most evident. Strong passwords should be enforced by every web application or public server. Standard user accounts, for example, must contain at least eight characters, a number, uppercase and lowercase letters, and a special character. Furthermore, servers should mandate password updates on a regular basis.\nBrute Force attack can also be avoided by the following methods:-  Limit the number of failed login attempts.\nBy altering the sshd_config file, you can make the root user unreachable via SSH.\nInstead of using the default port, change it in your sshd config file.\nMake use of Captcha.\nLimit logins to a certain IP address or range of IP addresses.\nAuthentication using two factors\nURLs for logging in that are unique\nKeep an eye on the server logs. Limit the number of failed login attempts. By altering the sshd_config file, you can make the root user unreachable via SSH. Instead of using the default port, change it in your sshd config file. Make use of Captcha. Limit logins to a certain IP address or range of IP addresses. Authentication using two factors URLs for logging in that are unique Keep an eye on the server logs.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "20. What do you mean by Man-in-the-Middle Attack?",
        "answer": "A cyber threat (a type of eavesdropping assault) in which a cybercriminal wiretaps a communication or data transmission between two people is known as a man-in-the-middle attack. Once a cybercriminal enters a two-way conversation, they appear to be genuine participants, allowing them to obtain sensitive information and respond in a variety of ways. The main goal of this type of attack is to acquire access to our company's or customers' personal information. On an unprotected Wi-Fi network, for example, a cybercriminal may intercept data passing between the target device and the network.  ",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "21. Differentiate between Information protection and information assurance.",
        "answer": "Information protection protects data from unauthorized access by utilizing encryption, security software, and other methods.\nInformation Assurance ensures the data's integrity by maintaining its availability, authentication, and secrecy, among other things. ",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "1. Differentiate between Stream Cipher and Block Cipher.",
        "answer": "The major distinction between a block cypher and a stream cypher is that a block cypher turns plain text into ciphertext one block at a time. Stream cypher, on the other hand, converts plain text into ciphertext by taking one byte of plain text at a time. Block Cipher Stream Cipher\nBy converting plaintext into ciphertext one block at a time, Block Cipher converts plain text into ciphertext. Stream Cipher takes one byte of plain text at a time and converts it to ciphertext.\nEither 64 bits or more than 64 bits are used in block ciphers. 8 bits are used in stream ciphers.\nThe ECB (Electronic Code Book) and CBC (Common Block Cipher) algorithm modes are utilized in block cipher (Cipher Block Chaining). CFB (Cipher Feedback) and OFB (Output Feedback) are the two algorithm types utilized in stream cipher (Output Feedback).\nThe Caesar cipher, polygram substitution cipher, and other transposition algorithms are used in the block cipher. Stream cipher uses substitution techniques such as the rail-fence technique, columnar transposition technique, and others.\nWhen compared to stream cipher, a block cipher is slower. When compared to a block cipher, a stream cipher is slower. Block Cipher Stream Cipher\nBy converting plaintext into ciphertext one block at a time, Block Cipher converts plain text into ciphertext. Stream Cipher takes one byte of plain text at a time and converts it to ciphertext.\nEither 64 bits or more than 64 bits are used in block ciphers. 8 bits are used in stream ciphers.\nThe ECB (Electronic Code Book) and CBC (Common Block Cipher) algorithm modes are utilized in block cipher (Cipher Block Chaining). CFB (Cipher Feedback) and OFB (Output Feedback) are the two algorithm types utilized in stream cipher (Output Feedback).\nThe Caesar cipher, polygram substitution cipher, and other transposition algorithms are used in the block cipher. Stream cipher uses substitution techniques such as the rail-fence technique, columnar transposition technique, and others.\nWhen compared to stream cipher, a block cipher is slower. When compared to a block cipher, a stream cipher is slower. Block Cipher Stream Cipher Block Cipher Stream Cipher Block Cipher Stream Cipher By converting plaintext into ciphertext one block at a time, Block Cipher converts plain text into ciphertext. Stream Cipher takes one byte of plain text at a time and converts it to ciphertext.\nEither 64 bits or more than 64 bits are used in block ciphers. 8 bits are used in stream ciphers.\nThe ECB (Electronic Code Book) and CBC (Common Block Cipher) algorithm modes are utilized in block cipher (Cipher Block Chaining). CFB (Cipher Feedback) and OFB (Output Feedback) are the two algorithm types utilized in stream cipher (Output Feedback).\nThe Caesar cipher, polygram substitution cipher, and other transposition algorithms are used in the block cipher. Stream cipher uses substitution techniques such as the rail-fence technique, columnar transposition technique, and others.\nWhen compared to stream cipher, a block cipher is slower. When compared to a block cipher, a stream cipher is slower. By converting plaintext into ciphertext one block at a time, Block Cipher converts plain text into ciphertext. Stream Cipher takes one byte of plain text at a time and converts it to ciphertext. By converting plaintext into ciphertext one block at a time, Block Cipher converts plain text into ciphertext. Stream Cipher takes one byte of plain text at a time and converts it to ciphertext. Either 64 bits or more than 64 bits are used in block ciphers. 8 bits are used in stream ciphers. Either 64 bits or more than 64 bits are used in block ciphers. 8 bits are used in stream ciphers. The ECB (Electronic Code Book) and CBC (Common Block Cipher) algorithm modes are utilized in block cipher (Cipher Block Chaining). CFB (Cipher Feedback) and OFB (Output Feedback) are the two algorithm types utilized in stream cipher (Output Feedback). The ECB (Electronic Code Book) and CBC (Common Block Cipher) algorithm modes are utilized in block cipher (Cipher Block Chaining). CFB (Cipher Feedback) and OFB (Output Feedback) are the two algorithm types utilized in stream cipher (Output Feedback). The Caesar cipher, polygram substitution cipher, and other transposition algorithms are used in the block cipher. Stream cipher uses substitution techniques such as the rail-fence technique, columnar transposition technique, and others. The Caesar cipher, polygram substitution cipher, and other transposition algorithms are used in the block cipher. Stream cipher uses substitution techniques such as the rail-fence technique, columnar transposition technique, and others. When compared to stream cipher, a block cipher is slower. When compared to a block cipher, a stream cipher is slower. When compared to stream cipher, a block cipher is slower. When compared to a block cipher, a stream cipher is slower.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "2. What do you mean by perimeter-based and data-based protection?",
        "answer": "Perimeter-based cybersecurity entails putting security measures in place to safeguard your company's network from hackers. It examines people attempting to break into your network and prevents any suspicious intrusion attempts. Perimeter-based cybersecurity The term \"data-based protection\" refers to the use of security measures on the data itself. It is unaffected by network connectivity. As a result, you can keep track of and safeguard your data regardless of where it is stored, who accesses it, or which connection is used to access it. data-based protection",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "3. Which is more reliable: SSL or HTTPS?",
        "answer": "SSL (Secure Sockets Layer) is a secure technology that allows two or more parties to communicate securely over the internet. To provide security, it works on top of HTTP. It works at the Presentation layer.\nHTTPS (Hypertext Transfer Protocol Secure) is a combination of HTTP and SSL that uses encryption to create a more secure surfing experience. The working of HTTPS involves the top 4 layers of the OSI model, i.e, Application Layer, Presentation Layer, Session Layer, and Transport Layer.\nSSL is more secure than HTTPS in terms of security. SSL (Secure Sockets Layer)  HTTPS (Hypertext Transfer Protocol Secure)   ",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "4. Differentiate between Symmetric and Asymmetric Encryption.",
        "answer": "Symmetric Encryption Asymmetric Encryption\nBoth encryption and decryption can be done using just one key. It takes two keys to encrypt and decrypt data respectively.\nIn this technique, the encryption system is very fast. In this technique, the encryption system is slow.\nWhen a huge volume of data must be transferred, it is used. When a small volume of data must be transferred, it is used.\nWhen compared to asymmetric key encryption, symmetric key encryption uses fewer resources. When compared to symmetric key encryption, asymmetric key encryption uses more resources.\nThe ciphertext is the same size as or smaller than the plain text. The ciphertext is the same size as or greater than the plain text.\nEg :- AES, DES Eg :- DSA and RSA Symmetric Encryption Asymmetric Encryption\nBoth encryption and decryption can be done using just one key. It takes two keys to encrypt and decrypt data respectively.\nIn this technique, the encryption system is very fast. In this technique, the encryption system is slow.\nWhen a huge volume of data must be transferred, it is used. When a small volume of data must be transferred, it is used.\nWhen compared to asymmetric key encryption, symmetric key encryption uses fewer resources. When compared to symmetric key encryption, asymmetric key encryption uses more resources.\nThe ciphertext is the same size as or smaller than the plain text. The ciphertext is the same size as or greater than the plain text.\nEg :- AES, DES Eg :- DSA and RSA Symmetric Encryption Asymmetric Encryption Symmetric Encryption Asymmetric Encryption Symmetric Encryption Asymmetric Encryption Both encryption and decryption can be done using just one key. It takes two keys to encrypt and decrypt data respectively.\nIn this technique, the encryption system is very fast. In this technique, the encryption system is slow.\nWhen a huge volume of data must be transferred, it is used. When a small volume of data must be transferred, it is used.\nWhen compared to asymmetric key encryption, symmetric key encryption uses fewer resources. When compared to symmetric key encryption, asymmetric key encryption uses more resources.\nThe ciphertext is the same size as or smaller than the plain text. The ciphertext is the same size as or greater than the plain text.\nEg :- AES, DES Eg :- DSA and RSA Both encryption and decryption can be done using just one key. It takes two keys to encrypt and decrypt data respectively. Both encryption and decryption can be done using just one key. It takes two keys to encrypt and decrypt data respectively. In this technique, the encryption system is very fast. In this technique, the encryption system is slow. In this technique, the encryption system is very fast. In this technique, the encryption system is slow. When a huge volume of data must be transferred, it is used. When a small volume of data must be transferred, it is used. When a huge volume of data must be transferred, it is used. When a small volume of data must be transferred, it is used. When compared to asymmetric key encryption, symmetric key encryption uses fewer resources. When compared to symmetric key encryption, asymmetric key encryption uses more resources. When compared to asymmetric key encryption, symmetric key encryption uses fewer resources. When compared to symmetric key encryption, asymmetric key encryption uses more resources. The ciphertext is the same size as or smaller than the plain text. The ciphertext is the same size as or greater than the plain text. The ciphertext is the same size as or smaller than the plain text. The ciphertext is the same size as or greater than the plain text. Eg :- AES, DES Eg :- DSA and RSA Eg :- AES, DES Eg :- DSA and RSA",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "5. What do you mean by a DDoS attack? How can you prevent it?",
        "answer": "It's a form of cyber threat or malicious effort in which fraudsters use Internet traffic to fulfill legitimate requests to the target or its surrounding infrastructure, causing the target's regular traffic to be disrupted. The requests originate from a variety of IP addresses, which might cause the system to become unworkable, overload its servers, cause them to slow down or go offline, or prevent an organization from performing its essential responsibilities.   The methods listed below will assist you in stopping and preventing DDOS attacks: Create a denial of the service response strategy.\nMaintain the integrity of your network infrastructure.\nUse fundamental network security measures.\nKeep a solid network architecture.\nRecognize the Warning Signs\nThink about DDoS as a service. Create a denial of the service response strategy. Maintain the integrity of your network infrastructure. Use fundamental network security measures. Keep a solid network architecture. Recognize the Warning Signs Think about DDoS as a service.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "6. Differentiate between IDS and IPS in the context of Cyber Security.",
        "answer": "  Intrusion Detection Systems (IDS) scan and monitor network traffic for signals that attackers are attempting to infiltrate or steal data from your network using a known cyber threat. IDS systems detect a variety of activities such as security policy violations, malware, and port scanners by comparing current network activity to a known threat database.\nIntrusion Prevention Systems (IPS) are located between the outside world and the internal network, in the same area of the network as a firewall. If a packet represents a known security hazard, an IPS will proactively prohibit network traffic based on a security profile.\nThe fundamental distinction is that an IDS is a monitoring system, whereas an IPS is a control system. IDS makes no changes to network packets, whereas IPS block packet delivery depending on the contents of the packet, similar to how a firewall blocks traffic based on IP address. Intrusion Detection Systems (IDS)  Intrusion Prevention Systems (IPS) ",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "7. What do you mean by Network Sniffing?",
        "answer": "Sniffing is a technique for evaluating data packets delivered across a network. This can be accomplished through the use of specialized software or hardware. Sniffing can be used for a variety of purposes, including: Capture confidential information, such as a password.\nListen in on chat messaging\nOver a network, keep an eye on a data package. Capture confidential information, such as a password. Listen in on chat messaging Over a network, keep an eye on a data package.  ",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "8. Differentiate between Black Box Testing and White Box Testing.",
        "answer": "Black Box Testing White Box Testing\nIt's a type of software testing in which the program's or software's internal structure is concealed. It is a method of software testing in which the tester is familiar with the software's internal structure or code.\nIt is not necessary to have any prior experience with implementation. It is not necessary to have prior experience with implementation.\nOn the basis of the requirement specifications paper, this testing can begin. This form of software testing begins once the detailed design document has been completed.\nIt takes the least amount of time. It takes the most amount of time.\nIt is the software's behavior testing. It is the software's logic testing.\nIt is relevant to higher levels of software testing. It is relevant to lower levels of software testing. Black Box Testing White Box Testing\nIt's a type of software testing in which the program's or software's internal structure is concealed. It is a method of software testing in which the tester is familiar with the software's internal structure or code.\nIt is not necessary to have any prior experience with implementation. It is not necessary to have prior experience with implementation.\nOn the basis of the requirement specifications paper, this testing can begin. This form of software testing begins once the detailed design document has been completed.\nIt takes the least amount of time. It takes the most amount of time.\nIt is the software's behavior testing. It is the software's logic testing.\nIt is relevant to higher levels of software testing. It is relevant to lower levels of software testing. Black Box Testing White Box Testing Black Box Testing White Box Testing Black Box Testing White Box Testing It's a type of software testing in which the program's or software's internal structure is concealed. It is a method of software testing in which the tester is familiar with the software's internal structure or code.\nIt is not necessary to have any prior experience with implementation. It is not necessary to have prior experience with implementation.\nOn the basis of the requirement specifications paper, this testing can begin. This form of software testing begins once the detailed design document has been completed.\nIt takes the least amount of time. It takes the most amount of time.\nIt is the software's behavior testing. It is the software's logic testing.\nIt is relevant to higher levels of software testing. It is relevant to lower levels of software testing. It's a type of software testing in which the program's or software's internal structure is concealed. It is a method of software testing in which the tester is familiar with the software's internal structure or code. It's a type of software testing in which the program's or software's internal structure is concealed. It is a method of software testing in which the tester is familiar with the software's internal structure or code. It is not necessary to have any prior experience with implementation. It is not necessary to have prior experience with implementation. It is not necessary to have any prior experience with implementation. It is not necessary to have prior experience with implementation. On the basis of the requirement specifications paper, this testing can begin. This form of software testing begins once the detailed design document has been completed. On the basis of the requirement specifications paper, this testing can begin. This form of software testing begins once the detailed design document has been completed. It takes the least amount of time. It takes the most amount of time. It takes the least amount of time. It takes the most amount of time. It is the software's behavior testing. It is the software's logic testing. It is the software's behavior testing. It is the software's logic testing. It is relevant to higher levels of software testing. It is relevant to lower levels of software testing. It is relevant to higher levels of software testing. It is relevant to lower levels of software testing.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "9. What do you mean by System Hardening?",
        "answer": "In general, system hardening refers to a set of tools and procedures for managing vulnerabilities in an organization's systems, applications, firmware, and other components.\nThe goal of system hardening is to lower security risks by lowering potential attacks and compressing the system's attack surface.\nThe many types of system hardening are as follows:   Hardening of databases\nHardening of the operating system\nHardening of the application\nHardening the server\nHardening the network Hardening of databases Hardening of the operating system Hardening of the application Hardening the server Hardening the network  ",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "10. Differentiate between HIDS and NIDS.",
        "answer": "HIDs look at certain host-based actions including what apps are run, what files are accessed, and what information is stored in the kernel logs. NIDs examine the flow of data between computers, often known as network traffic. They basically \"sniff\" the network for unusual activity. As a result, NIDs can identify a hacker before he can make an unlawful entry, whereas HIDs won't notice anything is wrong until the hacker has already gotten into the system.  ",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "11. What do you mean by Domain Name System (DNS) Attack?",
        "answer": "DNS hijacking is a sort of cyberattack in which cyber thieves utilize weaknesses in the Domain Name System to redirect users to malicious websites and steal data from targeted machines. Because the DNS system is such an important part of the internet infrastructure, it poses a serious cybersecurity risk.   These can be avoided by the following precautions:- Examine the DNS zones in your system.\nMake sure your DNS servers are up to current.\nThe BIND version is hidden.\nTransfers between zones should be limited.\nTo avoid DNS poisoning attempts, disable DNS recursion.\nUse DNS servers that are separated.\nMake use of a DDOS mitigation service. Examine the DNS zones in your system. Make sure your DNS servers are up to current. The BIND version is hidden. Transfers between zones should be limited. To avoid DNS poisoning attempts, disable DNS recursion. Use DNS servers that are separated. Make use of a DDOS mitigation service.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "12. Differentiate between VPN and VLAN.",
        "answer": "Companies use VLANs to consolidate devices that are dispersed across several remote sites into a single broadcast domain. VPNs, on the other hand, are used to transmit secure data between two offices of the same organization or between offices of different companies. Individuals also use it for their personal needs.\nA VLAN is a VPN subtype. VPN stands for Virtual Private Network, and it is a technology that creates a virtual tunnel for secure data transfer over the Internet.\nBecause it enables encryption and anonymization, a VPN is a more advanced but more expensive solution. A VLAN is useful for segmenting a network into logical sections for easier management, but it lacks the security characteristics of a VPN.\nA virtual local area network minimizes the number of routers required as well as the cost of deploying routers. A VPN improves a network's overall efficiency.\nExample of a VPN:- NordVPN, ZenMate     Example of a VPN  ",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "13. Differentiate between spear phishing and phishing?",
        "answer": "Spear phishing is a type of phishing assault that targets a small number of high-value targets, usually just one. Phishing usually entails sending a bulk email or message to a big group of people. It implies that spear-phishing will be much more personalized and perhaps more well-researched (for the individual), whereas phishing will be more like a real fishing trip where whoever eats the hook is caught.  ",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "14. What do you mean by ARP poisoning?",
        "answer": "Address Resolution Protocol Poisoning is a sort of cyber-attack that uses a network device to convert IP addresses to physical addresses. On the network, the host sends an ARP broadcast, and the receiver machine responds with its physical address.\nIt is the practice of sending bogus addresses to a switch so that it can associate them with the IP address of a legitimate machine on the network and hijack traffic. Address Resolution Protocol Poisoning   ",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "15. What do you mean by SQL Injection? How do you prevent it?",
        "answer": "SQL injection is a typical attack in which fraudsters employ malicious SQL scripts to manipulate backend databases and get access to sensitive data. The hostile actor can see, edit, or remove important company data, customer lists, or customers' personal details contained in the SQL database after the attack is successful.   The following practices can help you avoid SQL Injection attacks: Prepare statements ahead of time.\nUse Pre-defined Procedures\nVerify the user's input. Prepare statements ahead of time. Use Pre-defined Procedures Verify the user's input.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "16. What is the difference between virus and worm?",
        "answer": "A virus is a piece of harmful executable code that is attached to another executable file and can modify or erase data. When a virus-infected computer application executes, it takes action such as removing a file from the computer system. Viruses can't be managed from afar.\nWorms are comparable to viruses in that they do not alter the program. It continues to multiply itself, causing the computer system to slow down. Worms can be manipulated with remote control. Worms' primary goal is to consume system resources. ",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "17. What form of cookie might be used in a spyware attack?",
        "answer": "A tracking cookie, instead of a session cookie, would be used in a spyware attack because it would last through multiple sessions rather than just one.  ",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "18. How do you decide the placement of the encryption function?",
        "answer": "We must decide what to encrypt and where the encryption mechanism should be situated if encryption is to be used to counter attacks on confidentiality. Link and end-to-end encryption are the two main ways of encryption placement.\nEnd-to-end encryption, or E2EE, is a secure data transfer system in which data is encrypted and decrypted only at the endpoints, regardless of how many points it passes through in the middle of its virtual journey. This sort of encryption is an excellent technique to communicate in a secure and confidential manner. Because no one else has the key to decode it, no one in the middle will be able to read it.\nThe primary difference between link encryption and end-to-end encryption is that link encryption encrypts and decrypts all traffic at all points, not just at the endpoints. All data is encrypted as it travels along the communication line with this approach. When it reaches a router or another intermediary device, however, it is decrypted so that the intermediator can determine which direction to send it next.  End-to-end encryption  link encryption  ",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "19. What are Polymorphic viruses?",
        "answer": "Polymorphic viruses are sophisticated file infectors that may build changed versions of themselves in order to avoid detection while maintaining the same fundamental behaviors after each infection. Polymorphic viruses encrypt their programming and employ various encryption keys each time to alter their physical file makeup throughout each infection.\nMutation engines are used by polymorphic viruses to change their decryption routines every time they infect a machine. Because typical security solutions do not use a static, unchanging code, traditional security solutions may miss them. They are considerably more difficult to detect because they use complicated mutation engines that generate billions of decryption routines.   ",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "20. What do you mean by Active reconnaissance?",
        "answer": "Active reconnaissance is a type of computer assault in which an intruder interacts with the target system in order to gather information about weaknesses.\nPort scanning is commonly used by attackers to detect vulnerable ports, after which they exploit the vulnerabilities of services linked with open ports.\nThis could be done using automatic scanning or manual testing with tools like ping, traceroute, and netcat, among others. This sort of recon necessitates interaction between the attacker and the victim. This recon is faster and more precise, but it generates far more noise. Because the attacker must engage with the target in order to obtain information, the recon is more likely to be detected by a firewall or other network security device.  ",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    },
    {
        "question": "21. What do you mean by Forward Secrecy and how does it work?",
        "answer": "Forward secrecy is a property of certain key agreement protocols that ensures that the session keys will not be exposed if the server's private key is exposed. Perfect forward secrecy is another name for it (PFS).\nThe \"Diffie–Hellman key exchange\" algorithm is used to accomplish this.  Conclusion: Cybersecurity is critical because it safeguards all types of data against theft and loss. Sensitive data, personally identifiable information (PII), protected health information (PHI), personal information, intellectual property, data, and governmental and industry information systems all fall under this category.\nYour company won't be able to defend itself if it doesn't have a cybersecurity program.\nCyber security awareness is defined as the knowledge of an action taken to secure a company's information assets. When employees at a company are cyber security conscious, it implies they understand what cyber dangers are, the possible impact a cyber-attack will have on their company, and the procedures necessary to reduce risk and prevent cyber-crime from penetrating their online workspace.\nTo learn more about Cyber Security, you can go through the following references:-    Hacking: The Art of Exploitation by Jon Erickson\nPractical Malware Analysis by Michael Sikorski Hacking: The Art of Exploitation by Jon Erickson Practical Malware Analysis by Michael Sikorski  Useful Resources Useful Resources Security Engineer Salary\nCyber Security Salary in India\nCyber Security Projects Security Engineer Salary Security Engineer Salary Cyber Security Salary in India Cyber Security Salary in India Cyber Security Projects Cyber Security Projects",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "cyber-security"
    }
]